# Benjamin D. Killeen

Ph.D. Student, Johns Hopkins University
Department of Computer Science
3400 N Charles St
Baltimore, MD 21218, USA
killeen@jhu.edu

🛠 benjamindkilleen.com - ఊ arcade.cs.jhu.edu - ఊ cirl.lcsr.jhu.edu 🖙 Benjamin D. Killeen - ⊚ 0000-0003-2511-7929 - 🕠 benjamindkilleen - 🎔 @bdkilleen

#### Summary

A Ph.D. Student at Johns Hopkins University, I am a member of the Advanced Robotics and Interests Computationally Augmented Environments (ARCADE) research group and the Computational Interaction and Robotics Laboratory (CIRL). My research interests include computer vision, machine learning, and domain generalization, focusing on applications in robotic manipulation, medical imaging, and surgical robotics.

#### Education

**Ph.D., Computer Science**, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA.

08/2019 - present With Mathias Unberath and Gregory D. Hager.

**B.A., Computer Science with Honors, Physics Minor**, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA. 09/2015 - 06/2019 Thesis: Starting from Scratch: Deep Learning for Novel Scientific Image Analysis With Gordon Kindlmann.

### Research Experience

Research assistant, Department of Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA. 08/2020 - present With Mathias Unberath, Gregory D. Hager.

**Research Assistant**, Laboratory for Computational Sensing and Robotics, Johns Hopkins University, 08/2019 - 06/2020 Baltimore, MD, USA.

With Gregory D. Hager, Mathias Unberath, and Russel Taylor. Recipient: LCSR Fellowship for Outstanding Incoming Ph.D. Students.

Research assistant, Department of Computer Science, University of Chicago, Chicao, IL, USA. 03/2018 - 08/2019

With Gordon Kindlmann.

## Professional Experience

Computer Vision / Al Intern, Applied Research, Intuitive Surgical Inc., Sunnyvale, CA, USA. 06/2020 - 07/2020 With Omid Mohareri.

Software Development Intern, Cognitive Computing, Epic Systems, Verona, WI, USA.

06/2018 - 08/2018

Research Intern, IBM Research - Almaden, San Jose, CA, USA.

06/2017 - 08/2017

With Geoffry Burr.

## Selected Honors

Best Graduate Project Award, Computer Integrated Surgical Systems and Technology course, Johns05/2020Hopkins University, USA.COVID-19 Dataset Award, Kaggle04/2020

Intuitive Surgical Best Project Award, Deep Learning course, Johns Hopkins University, USA.

12/2019
Project: Enriching Unsupervised Feature Learning via Intermediate Subtasks.

With Michael Peven, Shaoyan Pan, Matthew Pittman.

## **Publications**

My publication list is also available on Google Scholar.

For our county-level dataset in [M-1].

10.1038/s41586-018-0180-5.

Peer-reviewed Journal Articles

A. Hundt, **B. D. Killeen**, H. Kwon, C. Paxton, GD Hager. "Good Robot!": Efficient Reinforcement

Learning for Multi-Step Visual Tasks with Sim to Real Transfer. IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters, vol.

5, no. 4, pp. 6724–6731, Oct. 2020. doi: 10.1109/LRA.2020.3015448.

S. Ambrogio, P. Narayanan, H. Tsai, R. M. Shelby, I. Boybat, C. di Nolfo, S. Sidler, M. Giordano, M. Bodini,

N. Farinha, **B. D. Killeen**, C. Cheng, Y. Jaoudi, G. W. Burr. Equivalent-accuracy accelerated neural-

network training using analogue memory. Nature, vol. 558, no. 7708, p. 60, Jun. 2018. doi:

Peer-reviewed Conference Papers

C. Gao, X. Liu, W. Gu, **B. D. Killeen**, M. Armand, R. Taylor, M. Unberath. Generalizing Spatial
C-2
Transformers to Projective Geometry with Applications to 2D/3D Registration. MICCAI **(to appear)**, 2020.

X. Liu, Y. Zhang, **B. Killeen**, M. Ishii, G. Hager, R. Taylor, M. Unberath. Extremely Dense Point
Correspondences using a Learned Feature Descriptor. Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on
Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, pp. 4847-4856, 2020.

**Preprints** 

J. Y. Wu\*, **B. D. Killeen**\*, P. Nikutta, M. Thies, A. Zapaishchykova, S. Chakraborty, M. Unberath Changes in Reproductive Rate of SARS-CoV-2 Due to Non-pharmaceutical Interventions in 1,417 U.S. Counties. medRxiv preprint, Jun. 2020, doi: 10.1101/2020.05.31.20118687.

\*Equal contribution.

**B. D. Killeen**, J. Y. Wu, K. Shah, A. Zapaishchykova, P. Nikutta, A. Tamhane, S. Chakraborty, J. Wei, T. Gao, M. Thies, M. Unberath. A County-level Dataset for Informing the United States' Response to COVID-19. arXiv preprint, 2020, arXiv:2004.00756.

M-1

M-2

Patents

G. W. Burr and **B. D. Killeen**. 2020. Efficient Processing of Convolutional Neural Network Layers Using Analog-memory-based Hardware. 20200117986, filed March 25, 2019, and issued April 16, 2020. https://uspto.report/patent/app/20200117986.

P-1

#### Teaching

Assistant Teaching

Machine Learning and Large Scale Data Analysis, Department of Computer Science, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA

03/2019 - 06/2019

With Prof. Yali Amit.

Wrote supplementary course material and held weekly lab sessions. Link: github.com/benjamindkilleen/lsda

Selected review: "Ben was incredibly patient during office hours and always responsive to student questions. In addition, he often presented demos during office hours or showed easier ways to handle the homework assignments; both were very helpful."

More reviews available at benjamindkilleen.com/teaching/2019-spring-lsda

Grading

Department of Computer Science, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA

01/2019 - 08/2019

- Scientific Visualization
- Introduction to Computer Science I
- Introduction to Computer Science II

Tutoring

Topics in Machine Learning, Baltimore, MD, USA.

06/2020 - present

GPA: 3.81

I tutor young people (middle- and high-school age) who are interested in CS and ML. More info at benjamindkilleen.com/teaching/2020-tutoring.

Selected Coursework

Graduate

Nonlinear Optimization II Computer Integrated Surgery II Computer Integrated Surgery I Deep Learning

Undergraduate

Unsupervised Learning\* Computer Vision

Machine Learning and Large Scale Data Analysis

Operating Systems Honors Combinatorics Honors Algorithms

Honors Discrete Mathematics Scientific Visualization Programming Languages Networks and Distributed Systems

\*Graduate level.

Creative Interests

**Creative nonfiction**: benjamindkilleen.com/blog **Science Fiction**: novel available by request.

Metadata

Available

- online: benjamindkilleen.com/markdown-cv.

- as a PDF: benjamindkilleen.com/files/cv.pdf.

Created based on markdown-cv by Eliseo Papa with styles based on David Whipp.

MIT License.

Last updated: September 2020